helpscoutdocs.com 2015-09-07

# Privacy Policy - Help Scout

_Last revised and effective as of: June 28, 2015_

Your privacy is extremely important to us. To better protect you, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on every page of this website.

This Privacy Policy relates to information collected by Brightwurks, Inc. dba Help Scout (referred to in this Privacy Policy as "Help Scout" "we" or "us" or "our") through your use of the Help Scout website and the Help Scout Services, features, and information available on the Help Scout website (which are collectively referred to in this Privacy Policy as the "Help Scout Service"). This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, a part of, and governed by our Terms of Service. 

By using the Help Scout Service, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you may not use the Help Scout Service.

As used in this Privacy Policy, the terms "using" and "processing" information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization.

  * What information does Help Scout collect?
  * Where and when is information collected?
  * When does Help Scout use information from third parties?
  * Does Help Scout collect information from children under 13 years of age?
  * What does Help Scout do with the information it collects?
  * When does Help Scout disclose information to third parties?
  * Does this Privacy Policy apply when I link to other websites or services?
  * Is the information collected through the Help Scout Service secure?
  * Could my information be transferred to other countries?
  * Is Help Scout Safe Harbor Compliant?
  * What choices do I have regarding the collection, disclosure and distribution of personally identifiable information?
  * Can I update or correct my personally identifiable information?
  * How will I know if there are any changes to this Privacy Policy?
  * Whom do I contact if I have any privacy questions?

### What information does Help Scout collect?

Depending on your use of the Help Scout Service, we collect two types of information: _personally identifiable information_ and _non-personally identifiable information_.

#### Personally Identifiable Information 

Personally identifiable information identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you. Examples of personally identifiable information include your name, company name, job title, address, e-mail address, telephone number, and billing and credit card information. 

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Non-personally identifiable information is information, any single of item of which, by itself, cannot be used to identify or contact you, including demographic information (such as age, profession, company industry, gender, current location, or zip code), IP addresses, browser types, domain names, and statistical data involving the use of the Help Scout Service. Certain non-personally identifiable information may be considered a part of your personally identifiable information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be identified. But the same pieces of information are considered non-personally identifiable information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-personally identifiable information (for example, your account preferences).

Back to top

### When does Help Scout use information from third parties?

Help Scout will collect End User Customer Data necessary to provide the Help Scout Service to you. "End User Customer Data" means information about your customers in the Help Scout Service, which includes but is not limited to, first name, last name, phone number and email address.

We may use End User Customer Data to look up and store additional Public Data in order to create a more complete customer profile. "Public Data" is defined as information received from a third party partner named FullContact, a Safe Harbor Certified company. Public Data may be claimed, edited or discarded from their systems by [following this link](http://www.fullcontact.com/privacy/claim) and is subject to their [Privacy Policy](http://www.fullcontact.com/privacy/).

If you would like to opt-out of our collection of End User Customer Data, you can do so by making a request via email. To disable this feature, you must be the Account Owner.

Back to top

### Where and when is information collected?

Help Scout will collect personally identifiable information that you submit to us. We may also receive personally identifiable information about you from third parties. For example, personally identifiable information is used to obtain credit/debit card authorization and prevent fraudulent transactions. It can also be used to further complete your Help Scout Services profile with an image or other form of information that is made publicly available by other online services.

#### Registering to Use the Help Scout Service and in the Course of Using the Help Scout Service.

You will be required to establish an account in order to take advantage of certain features of the Help Scout Service. If you wish to establish an account you will be required to provide us with information (including personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information). In addition, we may obtain your personally identifiable information from you if you identify yourself to us by sending us an e-mail with questions or comments.

#### Cookies and Page Tags

We may collect non-personally identifiable information passively using "cookies" and "page tags."

"[Cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie)" are small text files that can be placed on your computer or mobile device in order to identify your Web browser and the activities of your computer on the Help Scout Service and other websites. Cookies can be used to personalize your experience on the Help Scout websites (such as dynamically generating content on webpages specifically designed for you), to assist you in using the Help Scout Service (such as saving time by not having to reenter your name each time you use the Help Scout Service), to allow us to statistically monitor how you are using the Help Scout Service so that we can improve our offerings, and to target certain advertisements to your browser which may be of interest to you or to determine the popularity of certain content.

You do not have to accept cookies to use the Help Scout Service. Although most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, you may change your browser settings to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally. However, if you reject cookies, certain features or resources of the Help Scout websites may not work properly or at all and you may have a degraded experience.

"[Page tags](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug)," also known as web beacons or gif tags, are a web technology used to help track website or email usage information, such as how many times a specific page or email has been viewed. Page tags are invisible to you, and any portion of the Help Scout Service, including advertisements, or e-mail sent on our behalf, may contain page tags.

By using cookies and page tags together, we are able to improve the Help Scout Service and measure the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing campaigns.

Finally, you should be aware that this Privacy Policy does not govern the use of third-party websites or services or providers of third-party services.

#### Log Files

We collect non-personally identifiable information through our Internet log files, which record data such as user IP addresses, browser types, domain names, and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of the Help Scout Service. This information may be used to analyze trends, to administer the Help Scout Service, to monitor the use of the Help Scout Service, and to gather general demographic information. We may link this information to personally identifiable information for these and other purposes such as personalizing your experience on the Help Scout Service and evaluating the Help Scout Service in general.

Back to top

### Does Help Scout collect information from children under 13 years of age?

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. The Help Scout Service is not designed for or directed to children under the age of 13. We do not collect personally identifiable information from any person we actually know is under the age of 13.

Back to top

### What does Help Scout do with the information it collects?

In general, we use the information collected to provide you with a great overall experience using the Help Scout Service, to help us understand who uses the Help Scout Service, for internal operations such as operating and improving the Help Scout Service, to contact you for customer service and billing purposes and to facilitate the delivery of Help Scout advertising in some cases.

We use your information to send you a welcome e-mail after you create an account, when you are invited to Help Scout, or when you sign up for our newsletter. We also use your information to send other e-mail communication related to the Help Scout Service or website. For e-mail that is not transactional according to the standards set forth in the [CAN-SPAM Act of 2003](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAN-SPAM_Act_of_2003), we will provide an option to unsubscribe immediately.

If you identify yourself to us by sending us an e-mail with questions or comments, we may use your information (including personally identifiable information) to respond to your questions or comments, and we may file your questions or comments (with your information) for future reference. We may also use the information collected to send announcements and updates regarding the Help Scout Service or, if applicable, about your billing account status. You will not be able to unsubscribe from these Service announcements and updates as they contain important information relevant to your use of the Help Scout Service.

We may also use the information gathered to perform statistical analysis of user behavior or to evaluate and improve the Help Scout Service. We may link some of this information to personally identifiable information for internal purposes or to improve your experience with the Help Scout Service.

Back to top

### When does Help Scout disclose information to third parties?

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or the Help Scout Terms of Service or as specifically authorized by you, we will not disclose any information to third parties outside of Help Scout.

#### Laws and Legal Rights

We may disclose your information (including personally identifiable information) if we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in order to comply with an applicable statute, regulation, rule or law, a subpoena, a search warrant, a court or regulatory order, or other valid legal process. We may disclose personally identifiable information in special circumstances when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating the Help Scout Terms of Service, to detect fraud, or to protect the safety and/or security of our users, the Help Scout Service or the general public.

#### Third Parties Generally

Third parties may be able to independently directly collect personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information _without permission from Help Scout_ , and may include potential or actual advertisers, providers of advertising products or services (including vendors and website tracking services), merchants, affiliates and other actual or potential commercial partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties.

#### Outside Contractors

We may employ independent contractors, vendors and suppliers (collectively, "Outside Contractors") to provide specific services and products related to the Help Scout Service, such as hosting, credit card processing and fraud screening, and mailing list hosting for the Help Scout Service. In the course of providing products or services to us, these Outside Contractors may have access to information collected through the Help Scout Service, including your personally identifiable information. We require that these contractors agree to (1) protect the privacy of your personally identifiable information consistent with this Privacy Policy, and (2) not use or disclose your personally identifiable information for any purpose other than providing us with the products or services for which we contracted or as required by law.

#### Sale of Business

We reserve the right to transfer information to a third party in the event of a sale, merger or other transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of Help Scout or any of its Corporate Affiliates (as defined herein), or that portion of Help Scout or any of its Corporate Affiliates to which the Service relates, or in the event that we discontinue our business or file a petition or have filed against us a petition in bankruptcy, reorganization or similar proceeding, provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

#### Affiliates

We may disclose information (including personally identifiable information) about you to our Corporate Affiliates. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Corporate Affiliate" means any person or entity which directly or indirectly controls, is controlled by or is under common control with Help Scout, whether by ownership or otherwise. Any information relating to you that we provide to our Corporate Affiliates will be treated by those Corporate Affiliates in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Back to top

### Does this Privacy Policy apply when I link to other websites or services?

The Help Scout Service may provide you with access to other websites and services. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any websites or services other than the Help Scout Service. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of each and every such website and service. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by us through the Help Scout Service.

Back to top

### Is the information collected through the Help Scout Service secure?

We take precautions to protect the security of your information. We have physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to help safeguard, prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use your information. However, neither people nor security systems are foolproof, including encryption systems. In addition, people can commit intentional crimes, make mistakes or fail to follow policies. Therefore, while we use reasonable efforts to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If applicable law imposes any non-disclaimable duty to protect your personally identifiable information, you agree that intentional misconduct will be the standards used to measure our compliance with that duty.

Help Scout maintains ongoing Level 1 PCI compliance, adhering to stringent industry standards for storing, processing and transmitting credit card information online.

Help Scout also maintains ongoing compliance with the U.S. Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) and is able to process, maintain and store protected health information for any entities restricted by these regulations. On request, Help Scout will sign a business associate agreement (BAA) with your organization.

For more information about how Help Scout stores and secures customer and company data, please see our Security Policy.

Back to top

### Could my information be transferred to other countries?

Personally identifiable information collected on the Help Scout Service may be transferred from time to time to our offices or personnel, or to third parties, located throughout the world, and the Help Scout Service may be viewed and hosted anywhere in the world, including countries that may not have laws of general applicability regulating the use and transfer of such data. To the fullest extent allowed by applicable law, by using the Help Scout Service and submitting such information on it, you voluntarily consent to the trans-border transfer and hosting of such information. To the fullest extent allowed by applicable law, if you are a User accessing the Help Scout Service from a jurisdiction with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from those of the United States, please be advised that all aspects of the Help Scout Service are governed by the internal laws of the United States and the State of Delaware, USA, regardless of your location.

Back to top

### Is Help Scout Safe Harbor compliant?

Help Scout (under the name Brightwurks, Inc.) complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Help Scout has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Help Scout's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Brightwurks, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact us via email.

We have further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by our team, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint.

Back to top

### What choices do I have regarding the collection, disclosure and distribution of personally identifiable information?

Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will only use personally identifiable information for the purposes described above or as otherwise disclosed at the time we request such information from you. You must "opt in" and give us permission to use your personally identifiable information for any other purpose. You may also change your preference and "opt out" of receiving certain marketing communications from us by clicking the unsubscribe link included on the bottom of all such communications, or by contacting us via email.

#### Do Not Track

The term "Do Not Track" refers to a HTTP header offered by certain web browsers to request that websites refrain from tracking the user. We take no action in response to Do Not Track requests.

Back to top

### Can I update or correct my personally identifiable information?

You have the right to request the restriction of certain uses and disclosures of personally identifiable information as follows. You can contact us in order to (1) update or correct your personally identifiable information, (2) change your preferences with respect to communications and other information you receive from us, or (3) delete the personally identifiable information maintained about you on our systems (subject to the following paragraph), by [cancelling your account](http://docs.helpscout.net/article/473-cancel-account). Such updates, corrections, changes and deletions will have no effect on other information that we maintain, or information that we have provided to third parties in accordance with this Privacy Policy prior to such update, correction, change or deletion. To protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps (such as requesting a unique password) to verify your identity before granting you profile access or making corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

You should be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to us from our system. The need to back up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your personally identifiable information may exist in a non-erasable form that will be difficult or impossible for us to locate. We promise that promptly after receiving your request, all personally identifiable information stored in databases we actively use and other readily searchable media will be updated, corrected, changed or deleted, as appropriate, as soon as and to the extent reasonably practicable.

Back to top

### How will I know if there are any changes to this Privacy Policy?

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will not make changes that result in significant additional uses or disclosures of your personally identifiable information without notifying you of such changes via e-mail. We may also make non-significant changes to this Privacy Policy that generally will not significantly affect our use of your personally identifiable information, for which an e-mail is not required. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes. If any non-significant changes to this Privacy Policy are unacceptable to you, you must immediately contact us and, until the issue is resolved, stop using the Help Scout Service. Your continued use of the Help Scout Service following the posting of non-significant changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of those changes.

Back to top

### Whom do I contact if I have any privacy questions?

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or feel that we are not abiding by the terms of this Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Agent in any of the following ways:

  * By email.
  * By postal mail or courier:  
Attn: Privacy Agent  
Brightwurks, Inc. dba Help Scout  
131 Tremont Street  
3rd Floor  
Boston, MA 02111-1338 

Back to top

**By using the Help Scout Service, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Help Scout Service. Continued use of the Help Scout Service following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy that do not significantly affect the use or disclosure of your personally identifiable information will mean that you accept those changes.**
